shipspotting.com 2018-12-30

# Privacy Policy - ShipSpotting.com - Ship Photos and Ship Tracker

**Privacy**  
Your privacy is important to us. Please take a moment to read through our Privacy Policy that will tell you a bit about how we handle the information you supply and what other information we collect. 

General for all information submitted to Shipspotting is that we will never release name or other personal information about a Member without the permission of that Member. We reserve the right to distribute aggregated demographic information provided by Members. 

**Information we collect**  
In the registration process you submit personal data. This is called Personally Identifiable Information, and could be for example your name, age, and e-mail address. From time to time in the future we may offer additional features, services, and promotional opportunities that would require you to submit Personally Identifiable Information to participate. 

We also collect what is called Anonymous Information, exemplified by your IP address, the type of browser you use, the pages on our Sites that you have visited, and the advertisements that you have clicked on. WE DO NOT match your Personally Identifiable Information to your Anonymous Information. What you do and where you go is your business only. We use this aggregated information solely to be able to optimize the website based on how our visitors use it.

**Cookies**  
Like many Internet sites, we also use cookies. We do this to better support services for registered users and to collect statistics on how our website is used. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer and is stored on your hard drive. When you visit our Site(s) the cookie identifies your computer to us so that you do not have to re-register each time you visit. We may also use cookies to measure the traffic to our Sites and the use of different services and features of the Sites. 

Advertisers that appear on Shipspotting may place cookies on your computer and their use of the information stored on those cookies is subject to their own privacy policies. You should visit their sites to learn about their information practices. Advertisers or other companies do not have access to Shipspotting cookies.

You can enable cookies in your browser. This might result in loss of some features on Shipspotting.com, for example logon for registered users. Please also note that other websites that uses cookies might not be able to perform its best with cookies turned off. 

**Advertising practice**   
We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit [networkadvertising.org](http://networkadvertising.org/). 

**How to Enable Cookies**  
To enable cookies, follow the instructions below for the browser brand and version you are using.   
Mozilla Firefox (1.0 final release and earlier) : Go to the Tools menu, Select Options, Select the Privacy icon in the left panel, Check the box corresponding to Allow sites to set cookies, Click OK to save changes. 

Netscape 7.1/Mozilla 5.0 : Select Preferences from the Edit menu, Click on the arrow next to Privacy & Security in the scrolling window to expand, Under Privacy & Security, select Cookies., Select Enable all cookies, Click OK. 

Microsoft Internet Explorer 6.0+ : Select Internet Options from the Tools menu, Click on the Privacy tab, Click the Default button (or manually slide the bar down to Medium) under Settings, Click OK.

Microsoft Internet Explorer 5.x : Select Internet Options from the Tools menu, Click on the Security tab, Click the Custom Level button, Scroll down to the Cookies section. To enable: Set Allow cookies that are stored on your computer to Enable, Set Allow per-session cookies to Enable. Click OK. 

Microsoft Internet Explorer 4.x: Select Internet Options from the View menu, Click on the Advanced tab, Scroll down to find Cookies within the Security section, To enable: Select Always accept cookies. Click OK. 

Netscape Communicator 4.x: Select Preferences from the Edit menu. Find the Cookies section in the Advanced category. To enable: Select Accept all cookies (or Enable all cookies). Click OK.   
Password Security

The exchange between Shipspotting and the Member of information such as passwords or electronic mail may not be secure given the current state of the Internet. Shipspotting encourages Members to change their passwords frequently.

Communication  
Postings and other communications with Shipspotting are not private and may be published and edited at the discretion of Shipspotting unless specifically instructed otherwise.

**We hope that you will enjoy our service.**
